We will now talk about the collapse plugin,
现在让我们谈谈"折叠"插件
which is one of the Bootstrap JavaScript components.
这个插件是 Bootstrap 的 JavaScript 组件之一
We will see how we can make use of the collapse plugin to show and
我们将会学习如何在我们的网页中 利用折叠插件
hide content on our web page.
类显示或者隐藏某些内容
We will also examine how the collapse plugin has been leveraged with
我们会先探索折叠插件和我们的导航栏 之间的配合
our nav bar, in order to collapse the nav bar when you see that
亦即如何让我们的导航栏在屏幕尺寸为最小时
page on extra small screens.
自动折叠起来
And then reveal their nav bar items upon clicking of a button.
同时在用户点击某个按钮时能重新显现
We'll then see how we can make use of the collapse plugin together with the panel
在这之后 我们将会学习如何在 应用折叠插件的同时
class and the panel group classes to construct an accordion.
运用面板和面板组来实现一个折叠
The collapse plugin provides a very quick and
折叠插件向你提供了一个非常快速且简易的方式
easy way of showing and hiding content on our web page.
来实现显示或隐藏我们网页上的内容的功能
To toggle the show and hide behavior of our content we need to make use of either
我们希望 当用户点击一个按钮或一个链接时 我们特定的内容
a button or a link, which, when clicked, will toggle the content.
能够根据用户的动作来显示或隐藏
Now we'll look at a simple example of the collapse plugin in use and
接下来先让我们看一个应用折叠插件的栗子
then review the code thereafter.
对于其背后的代码 我们稍后再看
Taking a look at this simple example, you can see that we have some content
那么来看看这个简单的栗子 我们可以看到 在页面的左边
displayed on the left side here, and then a button on the right side.
显示了一些内容 而在右边则有一个按钮
So when you click on the button,
当你单击这个按钮时
the information will be either revealed or hidden.
你会发现在左边的内容会从显示到消失 又或从消失到显示
Right now, we start out with the information being shown on the page.
现在让我们来演示一下……
When you click on the button, the information is hidden and
当你单击这个按钮 内容便会消失
then when you click on the button again, the information is shown.
当你再次单击这个按钮时 内容又会再度显现
So this toggling of behavior is enabled by using the collapse plugin.
而这个神奇的"切换"功能就是用折叠插件实现的
Let's now review the source code for the collapse example that we just saw.
接下来让我们看看代码是怎么写的
So in this case, this collapse example is implemented by using a div
可以看到实现这个折叠的方法是用一个 div
with a class collapse and in applied to it.
并设置了 class="collapse in"
So we have two classes there.
这里我们用到了两个类
Collapse class and in class, together being applied to this div.
collapse 类和 in 类
So this is the div that contains the content
而在这个 div 下面就是我们的内容
that is going to be either shown or hidden by clicking on the button.
这些内容就是那些会一下消失一下出现的内容
So the next part is the button itself,
下一个环节自然就是按钮
which is going to trigger this toggling of the showing and hiding of the content.
这个按钮就是用来控制上述内容的消失和出现的
So this toggle button is implemented by using a standard a tag
我们用了一个 a 标签来实现这个按钮
with the button class as btn-primary, as you see in the example there.
同时设置了 class="btn btn-primary"
In addition, for the toggle to take place,
注意到为了实现之前那种神奇的切换
we have a data attribute called data-toggle.
我们还需要给按钮设置数据属性 data-toggle="collapse"
And then the data-toggle with the collapse attribute.
并将其目标用 href 表示
And the href of this a tag will refer to the ID
在这个栗子里 我们是用 id 来指定 按钮的作用对象的
of the div which contains the content that should be shown and
通过 href="#collapseExample" 来指定
hidden upon clicking of this button.
上面定义的那个 id 为 collapseExample 的 div
So, together with these, this code implements the collapsing and
那么这些代码加起来
hiding of the content for this simple example.
就实现了之前我们看的那个简单栗子的所有功能
Returning to the navigation bar that we have seen in the very first week,
现在让我们回到我们在一开始看到的那个导航栏
you'll recall that on extra small screens, we had a button on the right
你大概能想起当屏幕尺寸为最小时 在右边会出现一个按钮
side which when clicked would either reveal or hide the content.
当我们点击这个按钮时 它会进行内容的 显隐切换
Now, this action was actually implemented using the collapse plugin there.
你大概已经猜到了 这就是用折叠插件实现的
At that point,
当时我曾经说过我会在后面的某个模块
I mentioned that I would come back to this in one of the later modules.
详细地阐述这个按扭的实现
So now we will go back and reexamine the code that implemented this collapse
而现在正是详细阐述的时候
behavior and then understand how we are leveraging the collapse plugin
我们将会通过代码来理解
to enable this behavior.
折叠插件是怎么实现这个酷炫的显隐功能的
Looking back at the source code that we had seen earlier, you can now see that
看回这一段源代码 我们现在可以看到这个按钮
the button has been implemented there, with the data-toggle as collapse and
是设置了 data-toggle="collapse"
the data-target pointing to the navbar.
和 data-target="#navbar" 的
If you recall from the week one module where we explained navigation,
如果你回忆起我们第一周解释导航时
I had pointed out these two items there.
我曾经点出过这两者的话
Now, having known how the JavaScript components operate in Bootstrap,
如今的你既已经知道了 JavaScript 组件 作用于 Bootstrap 的原理
it all makes a lot more sense.
想必对当初我的言论会有更深的理解罢
So with this data-toggle that we implemented there,
总之 要点就是实现 data-toggle="collapse"
data-toggle collapse and the data-target is navbar.
和将 data-target 指向 navbar
Now the whole navigation element, the ul was enclosed inside a div,
至于整个导航的元素 则是一个封装在 div 中的 ul
which was given the class navbar-collapse and collapse.
同时需要将这个外层的 div 设置为 class="navbar-collapse collapse"
So what happens is that when you view this web page on an extra small screen,
于是 当你在最小的屏幕尺寸下浏览网页时
by default the navigation bar containing the navigation elements is collapsed.
导航栏的默认状态是折叠起来
Because this div has only been given the collapse class there.
因为那个 div 只有一个 collapse 类
It has not been given the in together with the collapse class.
而没有一个表示显示的 in 类
If you give the in class together with the collapse class
而如果你一开始就设置了 in 类的话
the div will start in the shown mode there,
那个 div 就会显示出来
which means that the content will actually be shown on the screen.
也就是看上去和平时一样
So since we avoided the use of the in class,
所以既然这里我们没有用 in 类
the content will start in the collapsed border.
那些内容自然就被折叠了
When the button is clicked, the content will revealed.
而当我们单击这个按钮时 内容会显示出来
And when the button is again clicked, the content will be hidden.
而再次点击后 内容又会被隐藏
So that is how the navigation bar worked for
这个神奇的功能正是通过在导航栏上
the collapse plugin that we used earlier.
应用折叠插件来实现的
So that is how the navigation bar with the collapse plugin
这些种种 阐述了如何在最小屏幕尺寸下
together worked for the extra small screens.
通过在导航栏上应用折叠插件来达到一种 很好的效果
Going to back to our about our aboutus.html page.
回到我们的 aboutus.html 页面
Now I have replaced the entire tabbed navigation that I had for
我们接下来需要用一个折叠来代替 我们之前实现的
the corporate leadership information earlier, using an accordion.
这整个显示合伙企业领导信息的页签导航
The accordion works by using a panel group
我们将用一个面板组来实现这个折叠
together with a set of panels that enclose the content.
顾名思义的 面板组将会封装一系列面板
We have already seen the panel component in Bootstrap in the previous module.
我们已经在之前的单元中学过怎么实现面板
So let's see the accordion in action.
现在我们将活用面板来实现一个折叠
So, when you look at the web page, you will see that the web page starts out with
我们需要实现的效果是 当我们一开始 点进这个网页时
that first panel containing the details of the CEO being shown,
第一个面板的内容将会呈现
and the remaining panels being hidden.
同时其它面板的内容将被隐藏
Now, if you click on any one of the other panels, then the result is that
而当你点击其它的面板时
that particular panel gets revealed, and the remaining panels get hidden.
那个特定的面板的内容将会呈现
So you can see the behavior with the remaining panels too.
同时其它内容将被隐藏
So you can click on any one of those panels heading and
我们可以一个一个地
then the contents of the panel will be revealed,
反复地
while the contents of the remaining panels will be hidden.
进行这种显隐状态的切换
So this is the accordion behavior that I was talking about.
而这就是所谓的折叠了
Let's now quickly look at how we implement this accordion behavior
接下来让我们快速地看一下
using the panel group and the panels.
如何通过面板和面板组来实现它
Going to the source code, we now see the code for
我们可以看到
the accordion shown on the left-side and
左侧的代码实现的
the accordion itself as seen on the web page shown on the right side.
就是右边的效果
So when you look at the code on the left side you see that we have enclosed
仔细地看代码 你可以发现我们将所有的内容
the entire content in an outer div which has been given the class as panel-group,
都封装进了一个外层的 div 里面
and has been given the ID as accordion there.
而这个 div 被设置了 class="panel-group" 和 id="accordion"
And inside there, individual panels are enclosing the actual content.
同时在这个 div 的下面 我们可以看到许多 被封装起来的
So, the individual panels, as you can see here,
不同的面板
has a panel-heading and the panel-body down below here.
而这些面板都有一个标题和一个内容体
In the panel-heading, you can see that I am using
在标题里 我用了带 class="panel-title" 的 h3 标签
the h3 class with the panel title, and then inside the h3 class,
而在这个 h3 标签中我又用了一个 a 标签
I am including the name of the corporate leader.
来装这个公司领导人的名字
And this name is enclosed inside an a tag
同时 这个 a 标签还被设置了 role="button"
with the role button and the data-toggle given as collapse.
和 data-toggle="collapse"
So, now you can see why clicking on that link or
这些加在一起 就实现了我们之前
corresponding to the corporate leader opens and
看到的那种显隐状态切换
closes that particular panel content there.
的效果
So, the data-toggle and then the href, obviously,
当然在 a 标签的 data-toggle 后面要接一个 href
pointing to the panel itself down below.
这个 href 应当指向下面相应定义的面板
In addition,
除了 Glyphicons 之外
I am also giving another data attribute called data-parent with the accordion.
我还设置了另一个数据属性 data-parent="#accordion"
So, this is declaring that this panel forms
这声明了这个面板时“属于” accordion 的
one of the panels in the panel group there with the id accordion.
而“同属”一个含有 class="panel-group" 属性的 div
So this is why the data-parent is given the id as accordion,
的面板中 只能有一个被显示而其它都需被隐藏
which is the id of the panel group there.
这就是为什么我们需要将 data-parent 指向最外层的那个 div
Now, the content itself is enclosed inside
至于面板的内容 则会被封装进一个 div
a panel-collapse class with a collapse and in here.
这个 div 会被设置 class="panel-collapse collapse in"
Now this means that this particular content will start out
注意到有了 in 就表示在刚打开界面时
by being shown on the screen.
这一块内容会被显示出来
So that is why on the right-hand side, you can see that the CEO's panel
所以当我们只对其中一个面板应用 in 类时
starts out as open, but the remaining panels we will not use the in class for
就会呈现右图这样的
the remaining panel collapses.
只有一个面板内容被呈现
We will only use the collapse class there.
而其它面板内容都被隐藏的效果
And note also that the ID is given as Peter, which corresponds to the href
注意到我将 id 的名字都设置好了
that you gave for the a tag earlier there.
这些 id 能很好地对应上之前 a 标签里的 href
Inside this panel-collapse,
而在 panel-collapse 里面
we are enclosing the actual content, the p element that we had,
我们将会用一个 p 标签来封装那些 我们想要呈现的内容
with the description inside a inner div, with the class panel-body.
而这个 p 标签的外层需为一个设置了
So the outer div enables the collapse behavior to work.
class="panel-body" 的 div
And the inner div actually contains the panel-body,
也就是外层 div 保证了折叠的功能
which is displayed on the screen on the right side.
内层 div 包含了实际的内容
So, when you click on the name of the corporate leader,
那么 当我们做完了上述种种工作
the corresponding panel is either hidden or revealed.
当我们将所有面板封装进了 同一个 panel-group 下
Because of the enclosing of all these panels
当我们将这些面板的 data-parent 同时指向了这个 panel-group
inside a panel group with the id accordion, and
当我们很好地设置了各个类
the data-parent attribute specified as accordion for each of the panels.
当我们很好地设置了各个 id
When you click on any one of those panel headings,
之后
that particular panel will be revealed and will also result in the remaining panel
我们之前看的那种显隐状态切换的效果
bodies being collapsed correspondingly.
就全部实现完毕了
So, this is what implements the accordion behavior that you see on the web page.
以上 就是关于如何实现折叠的全部内容 【翻译 - Carefree0910】